Guide to the Robertson family papers, 1820-1907.
Robertson family papers, 1820-1907.
- August 12, 1846 - October 26, 1846 11 items (Folder 9)
  - October 26, 1846 (Folder 9)
    Form letter from N. S. Benton, Supt. Common Schools, Secretary's Office, Dept. of Common Schools, Albany to County Superintendent SR. Blank reports for district trustees are available.
- February 19, 1847 - October 14, 1847 11 items (Folder 10)
  - February 19, 1847 (Folder 10)
    Form letter from Delphian Institute of Union College, Schenectady to SR as a former member asking for a donation of either money or books to keep, in the Institute's attempt to fit up a reading room.
  - March 15, 1847 (Folder 10)
    From Alonzo Wynkoop, County Supt. of Chemung, to SR, Ithaca. Three counties, Tompkins, Steuben and Chemung are planning a union Teachers' Institute to which all the neighboring counties are being invited. The letter from Wynkoop is to inform SR of what has been planned so far; who the principal speakers will be, a sample of the notice to appear in the newspapers (handwritten).
  - April 10, 1847 (Folder 10)
    From Alonzo Wynkoop, Chemung, to SR, Ithaca. Letter gives SR more news about the union Institute informing him that notices have been sent to newspapers. Wynkoop has had no definite answer from those whom he has asked to address the Institute, If all else fails, he will call upon SR to deliver an address. (first mention is made of Robertson being married as Wynkoop says ".. .and shall hope to meet your bride,... .")
  - May 6, 1847 (Folder 10)
    From N. S. Benton, State of New York Secretary's Office, Dept. of Common Schools, Albany to SR. Letter says that land is liable to assessment by a district if it lies partially within that district and if the owner/occupant resides on the land in that particular district.
  - June 23, 1847 (Folder 10)
    From B. F. Winegar, a member of SR's fraternity, Sigma Phi, at Union College, to SR. The fraternity needs donations from members to build a membership hall. This letter contains second mention of SR having recently married.
  - July 24, 1847 (Folder 10)
    From Cyrus Robertson, Albion, Michigan, to his brother, SR.
  - September 1, 1847 (Folder 10)
    Printed circular from N. S. Benton, Secretary's Office, Dept. of Common Schools, Albany, to County Supt. SR. The circular contains information pertaining to the reduction of the amount of gratuity allowed to pupils.
  - October 4, 1847 (Folder 10)
    From Benj[amin] Cook, Penn Yan to SR. Cook will not be able to attend the whole of an Institute to lecture and teach Phonography but will be present for the second week.
  - October 7, 1847 (Folder 10)
    From J. S. (?) Holmes, Deputy Supt. of Common Schools, State of New York, Secretary's Office, Dept. of Common Schools, to SR,. Letter concerns a discrepancy concerning sums of money received during the current year, which appear in SR's abstract of Town Supt.'s Reports.
  - October 14, 1847 (Folder 10)
    October 14 letter from James Redfield of Lyons, County Supt. for Wayne County to SR introducing Dr. Calvin Cutler, author of a book on physiology; on same sheet.
  - October 19, 1847 (Folder 10)
    October 19 letter from. Calvin Cutler, Ithaca to SR sending SR a copy of the above mentioned book.
- January 16, 1848 - June 30, 1852 (Folder 11)
  - January 16, 1848 (Folder 11)
    From Philip and Sarah Robertson, Conneaut, Ohio, to SR.
  - March 26, 1848 (Folder 11)
    From B. R. King & P. R. King, Middleport, N.Y. to their brother and sister, SR and ? (his wife?) sleighing; RR correspondence.
  - March 27, 1848 (Folder 11)
    From W. Van Wyck, Union College to SR. The letter asks for funds for the finishing of the Conclave hall for the Sigma Phi fraternity at Union College.
  - July 11, 1848 (Folder 11)
    From H. (?) McGonegal, Baldwinsville, to SR asking SR for a recommendation for a teaching position.
  - November 16, 1849 (Folder 11)
    From O. O. Wickham, Clinton Hall (pm Williamsburg), N.Y. to SR. Wickham requests a list of the names and addresses of the teachers in the area so that he may send them ".. .some valuable information which will be to their advantage and advance the cause of education."
  - June 30, 1852 (Folder 11)
    Printed circular from Association of Former Students of Cortland Academy to SR; letter asks for donations for a fund to be given to Mr. Wollworth, by his former pupils upon his resignation.
- Undated 5 items (Folder 12)
  - July 17 (Folder 12)
    From Thomas (?) Dwight, Albany, to SR. Letter concerns an Institute not being held. There is also mention made of an attack upon the present school system being made at a teachers' convention.
  - August 2 (Folder 12)
    From Thomas (?) Dwight, Albany, to SR. Dwight is asking SR for information of the upcoming Tompkins County Institute.
  - November 4 (Folder 12)
    From Peter Selover, Homer, to SR. The author of the letter had been promised a letter he did not receive. He is now appealing to SR for a certificate and/or a letter of recommendation.
  - Undated (Folder 12)
    Printed circular advertising an arithmetic series.
  - Undated (Folder 12)
    Printed circular advertising Mitchell's Map Establishment.
- Miscellaneous Letters and Receipt (not involving SR), 20 items 1821-1850 (Folder 13)
  - October 29, 1821 (Folder 13)
    From Adjt. General W. L. Marcy, Troy, to General Samuel Hatheway, Homer. General Marcy has been asked to give an opinion about whether or not officers who did not parade their companies on a certain required date should be punished. If they did not know that they were required to perform a duty, then they can not be punished for failing to fulfill the obligation. Note: Xerox copy placed in Hatheway Family Papers, Ace. #2281.
  - April 28, 1828 (Folder 13)
    Receipt for pay as teacher in District #4, town and county unnamed; signed by Israel Roberts.
  - March 4, 1836 (Folder 13)
    From Ebby Hyde, Farmer [Interlaken], to Doctor Frederick Hyde, Cortland Village. Augustus (?) has just left Ebby Hyde's after a visit. Ebby says that he regrets that Frederick could not have been there at the same time as Augustus but says it was not possible. Ebby talks of a trip he is soon to start upon and says he is looking forward to Frederick's visit.
  - July 14, 1837 (Folder 13)
    From G. Woodruff, Buffalo, to Dr. Frederick Hyde, Cortlandville. Personal letter containing family news and other items of gossip. Woodruff teases Hyde about his (Hyde's) "unpatriotic bachelorhood."
  - July 20, 1842 (Folder 13)
    From C. F. Woodruff, Ithaca, to father (step-father?, father-in-law?) P. Pelton of Monticello, N.Y. Trip by stagecoach from Monticello to Ithaca.
  - December 18, 1843 (Folder 13)
    From J. W. French of Albion, New York, to Mr. E. B. Walsworth, of Walworth, Wayne Co. concerning a report to be made out re the Walworth Academy of which Walsworth is principal.
  - January 22, 1844 (Folder 13)
    From James S. McRie, Union College, to E. B.. Walsworthth asking for a teaching position at the Walworth Academy where Walsworth is principal.
  - February 21, 1844 (Folder 13)
    From George Loomis of Genesee Wesleyan Seminary, Lima, Livingston Co., to E. B. Walsworth saying that visit to "Lyceum" at Walworth, Wayne Co. at present would not be possible.
  - May 30, 1844 (Folder 13)
    From Joseph Rosenkrans of Fort Plain to Mr. Walsworth of Union College: Request that Walsworth deliver sermon in place of Rosenkrans while he (Rosenkrans) must be away.
  - September 30, 1845 (Folder 13)
    From Caleb Clark, Truxton, to Dr. Frederick Hyde, Cortland (ville). Clark is ill and wishes Dr. Hyde to prescribe some medicine for him.
  - May 26, 1846 (Folder 13)
    From John Foster, Union College, to E. B. Walsworth at Auburn Theological Seminary. In doubt as to date of Auburn Commencement and "propriety" of his [Foster's] addressing the body.
  - June 12, 1846 (Folder 13)
    From Silas C. Brown, W. Bloomfield, to his nephew E. B. Walsworth, Auburn, N.Y. Family matters.
  - December 17, 1846 (Folder 13)
    From Rev. E. G. Townsend, Sackets Harbor, to E. Walsworth, Auburn. Personal news and comment.
  - March 25, 1847 (Folder 13)
    From H. W. Parker, Mexico, N.Y., to E. B. Walsworth, Auburn Theological Seminary. (Rev.) Parker wishes someone to substitute for him for four Sabbaths and asks Walsworth's assistance in securing someone.
  - November 7, 1847 (Folder 13)
    From Albert West, Troy to Ira G. Fellows. Will be 21 11/8 (b. 1826). Visit to N.Y.C. - theatre-going, attending Trinity Church.
  - May 7, 1848 (Folder 13)
    From Albert West, Troy, to Ira G. Fellows, Pulaski. Mutual friends and daily activities.
  - May 8, 1848 (Folder 13)
    From Henry L. Young of Avon, to Rev. E. B. Walsworth, Union Theological Seminary, N.Y. Is invited to assume Presbyterian pastorate at Avon. "This is missionary ground... ."
  - November 5, 1848 (Folder 13)
    From Albert West, Troy, to Ira G. Fellows. Personal news.
  - February 4, 1850 (Folder 13)
    From Albert West, Troy, to Ira G. Fellows. Social news--sleigh rides.
  - April 12, 1850 (Folder 13)
    From Albert West, Troy, to Ira G. Fellows, Pulaski. Maple sugar making news from California; "'tell the boys to let well enough alone and stay at home."
- Miscellaneous Madison and Chenango County School District Records, 3 items. (Folder 14)
  - July 13, 1884 (Folder 14)
    Warrant from Almon Baker, trustee of School District #8, Cazenovia, Madison County ordering him to receive school taxes; a list of taxable inhabitants and amounts they owe. 1 item (2 pcs.)
  - November 18, 1895 (Folder 14)
    Order to Tax Collector to pay wages earned by Addie Warner as teacher in School District #9, Town of Lincklaen, Chenango County.
  - Undated (Folder 14)
    A handwritten catalogue of books (15 vols.) belonging to School District #2, Town of Lincklaen.